Guide to the Microwave Research Institute Technical Reports RG.031
Poly Archives at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
- Series III: Report number PIBMRI 201-300, 1949-1950
  - Production of Metallized Film Glass Attenuator Plates, PIBMRI-227-49, 1949 November 10; Graham, Clifford T. (Volume PIBMRI-227-49)
    PIB-172
    R-227-49
    Contract No. W28-099-ac-197
  - Phase-Shift Data of Metallized-Glass Attenuator for Frequency Range 18,000 - 25,500 mc/sec, PIBMRI-228-49, 1949 December 9; Giordano, Anthony B.; Steinman, Beulah (Volume PIBMRI-228-49)
    PIB-173
    R-288-49
    Contract No. W28-009-ac-197
  - A Study of Self-Saturating Magnetic Amplifiers, Part I: Steady State Response of Half-Wave Circuit, PIBMRI-229-49, 1949 December 30; Smith, Edward J. (Volume PIBMRI-229-49)
    PIB-174
    R-229-49
  - A Study of Self-Saturating Magnetic Amplifiers, Part II: Investigation of Rectifier Reverse Current Flow, And Steady State Analysis of Full-Wave And Doubler Circuits, PIBMRI-230-50, 1950 February 20; Smith, Edward J. (Volume PIBMRI-230-50)
    PIB-175
    R-230-50
  - A Study of Self-Saturating Magnetic Amplifiers, Part III: Influence of Control Circuit Resistance on Steady State Performance, PIBMRI-231-50, 1950 March 27; Smith, Edward J. (Volume PIBMRI-231-50)
    R-231-50
    PIB 176
    Project Designation NR-075-214
  - Preliminary Report on Design of Metallized-Glass-Dissipative-Wall Variable Waveguide Attenuator, PIBMRI-232-50, 1950 April 6; Bogner, Richard; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-232-50)
    R-232-50
    PIB 177
  - Characteristics of Communication Systems, PIBMRI-233-50, 1951 June 18; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-233-50)
    R-233-50
    PIB 178
    Contract No. W28-099-ac-481
  - Equivalent Circuits for Slots in rectangular Waveguide, PIBMRI-234-50, 1951 August; Oliner, Arthur A. (Volume PIBMRI-234-50)
    AD 653 302
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.12-52, PIB-180.12 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System June 1, 1952 to August 31, 1952 prepared under contract AF-28(099)-236 for Rome Air Development Center, PIBMRI-235.12-52, 1952 September 18; Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-235.12-52)
    PIB 180.12
    AD 4058
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.13-52, PIB-180.13 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System September 1, 1952 to November 30, 1952 prepared for Rome Air Development Center Contract AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.13-52, 1952 December 12; Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-235.13-52)
    R-235.13-52
    PIB 180.13
    AD 4736
  - Progress Report R-235.14-53, PIB-180.14 on Development of a Broadband Antenna Multicoupler System December 1, 1952 to February 28, 1953 for Rome Air Development center Contract No. AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.14-53, 1953 March 9; Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-235.14-53)
    R-235.14-53
    PIB 180.14
    AD 9821
  - Interim Engineering Report on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System for the period March 1, 1953 to May 31, 1953, PIBMRI-235.15-53, 1953 June 4; Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-235.15-53)
    R-235.15-53
    PIB 180.15
    AD 16894
    Contract No. AF-28(099)-236
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.16-53, PIB-180.16 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System June 1, 1953 to August 31, 1953 prepared for Rome Air Development Center Contract AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.16-53, Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-235.16-53)
    R-235.16-53
    PIB 180.16
    AD 32 557
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.17-53, PIB-180.17 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System September 1, 1953 to November 30, 1953 prepared for Rome Air Development Center Contract AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.17-53, 1953 December 14; Carlin, Herbert J.; Cohen, Morris (Volume PIBMRI-235.17-53)
    R-235.17-53
    PIB 180.17
    AD 28 218
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.18-54, PIB-180.18 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System December 1, 1953 to February 28, 1954 prepared for Rome Air Development Center Contract AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.18-54, 1954 March 19; Carlin, Herbert J.; Cohen, Morris (Volume PIBMRI-235.18-54)
    R-235.18-54
    PIB 180.18
    AD 36 832
  - Interim Engineering Report R-235.19-54, PIB-180.18 on Development of Broadband Antenna Coupler System March 1 to May 31 1954 prepared for Rome Air Development Center Contract AF-28(099)-236, PIBMRI-235.19-54, 1954 June 17 (Volume PIBMRI-235.19-54)
  - Metallized Film Attenuator Plates Production and Quality Control, PIBMRI-236-50, 1950 September 28; Schleuning, Hubert W. (Volume PIBMRI-236-50)
    R-236-50
    PIB 181
  - A Preliminary Study of Communication Receiver Location to Minimize Radar Interference, PIBMRI-237-50, 1950 November 10; Rosenthal, Saul W. (Volume PIBMRI-237-50)
    R-237-50
    PIB 182
    Contract No. AF-28(009)8
  - A Study of Self-Saturating Magnetic Amplifiers, Part IV: Transient Response, PIBMRI-238-50, 1950 December 11; Smith, Edward J. (Volume PIBMRI-238-50)
    R-238-50
    PIB 183
  - Progress Report for the Period of January 1, 1952 to March 31, 1951 on Navy Contract N0bsr-52078 on Connector Development, PIBMRI-239.2-51, 1951 May 5; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-239.2-51)
    R-239.2-51
    PIB-184
    ATI 196 188
  - Progress Report for the Period of July 1, 1952 to September 30, 1952 on Navy Contract N0bsr-52078 on Connector Development, PIBMRI-239.8-52, 1952 November 18; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-239.8-52)
    R-239.8-52
    PIB 184.8
    AD 32 567
  - Progress Report R-239.9-53, PIB-184.9 on Connector Development October 1, 1952 to December 31, 1952 for Bureau of Ships Contract N0bsr-52078 Index No. NE-110718, PIBMRI-239.9-53, 1953 February 27; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-239.9-53)
    R-239.9-53
    PIB-1849
  - Progress Report R-239.10-53, PIB-184.10 on Connector Development January 1, 1953 to March 31, 1953 for Bureau of Ships Contract N0bsr-52078 Index No. NE-110718, PIBMRI-239.10-53, 1953 May 29; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-239.10-53)
    R-239.10-53
    PIB 184.10
    AD 48 384
  - Progress Report R-239.15-55, PIB-184.15 on Connector Development August 1, 1954 to October 31, 1954 for Bureau of Ships Contract N0bsr-52078 Index No. NE-110718, PIBMRI-239.15-55, 1955 january 26; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-239.15-55)
    R-239.15-55
    PIB 184.15
    AD 56 043
  - Design and Operation of Audio Filters for Suppression of Periodic Pulse Noise, PIBMRI-245-51, 1951 May 3; Davis, Arthur S. (Volume PIBMRI-245-51)
    R-245-51
    PIB 186
    Contract AF-28(099)-8
  - Coding Processes for Bandwidth Reduction in Picture Transmission, PIBMRI-246-51, 1951 August 30; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-246-51)
    R-246-51
    PIB 187
  - The Effects of Noise on Range Tracking Systems, PIBMRI-247-51, 1951 June 15; Ruina, Jack (Volume PIBMRI-247-51)
    R-247-51
    PIB 188
    Contract No. AF-28(099)8
  - Two D.C. Bridges for Bolometer Power Measurements, PIBMRI-248-51, 1951 June 18; Carlin, Herbert J.; Torgow, Eugene (Volume PIBMRI-248-51)
    R-248-51
    PIB 189
    Contract No. W28-099-ac-503
  - Semi-Technical Report on Impedance Measurement, PIBMRI-249-51, 1951 June 12; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-249-51)
    R-249-51
    PIB 190
    Contract No. W33-038-ac-18115
  - Memorandum on Dual Antenna Interface Reduction System, PIBMRI-251-51, 1951 July 12; Carlin, Herbert J.; Vallese, Lucio M. (Volume PIBMRI-251-51)
    R-251-51
    PIB 192
    Contract No. AF-30(120)490
  - On the Uniformity of Evaporated Metallic Film Attenuator Plates, PIBMRI-252-51, 1951 September 10; Schleuning, Hubert W. (Volume PIBMRI-252-51)
    R-252-51
    PIB 193
    Index No. NE-100-402
  - Spherical Transmission Line Theory, PIBMRI-253-51, 1952 January; Felson, Leopold B. (Volume PIBMRI-253-51)
    R-253-51
    PIB-194
    ATI 135946
    Contract AF 19(122)-3
  - Memorandum on Noise Figure of FPS-3 Radar, PIBMRI-254-51, 1951 August 30; Carlin, Herbert J.; Griemsmann, John W. E. (Volume PIBMRI-254-51)
    R-254-51
    PIB-195
    Contract No. AF-30(120)-483
  - Memorandum on the Use of a Filter Pair for a Two Radar-Common Antenna Multiplexer, PIBMRI-255-51, 1951 September 7; Bresler, Aaron; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-255-51)
    R-255-51
    PIB 196
    ATI 135 116
    Contract No. AF-30(120)-490
  - Letter Report, PIBMRI-256.14-52, 1952 July 22; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-256.14-52)
    R-256.14-52
    PIB 197.14
    AD 47061
  - Letter Report, PIBMRI-256.15-52, 1952 September 9; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-256.15-52)
    PIB 197.15
    AD 46954
    Contract No. DA-44-009-eng-830
  - Validity of the Substitution Principle in Power Measurement, PIBMRI-257-51, 1951 September 24; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-257-51)
    R-257-51
    PIB 198
  - A Brief Description of the Digital Radar Relay Developed by the Air Force cambridge Research Laboratories, PIBMRI-258-51, 1951 October 15; Lynch, W. A. (Volume PIBMRI-258-51)
    R-258-51
    PIB 199
    ATI 140247
  - Coaxial Line Segment for Microwave Diodes (Vacuum Seal), PIBMRI-259-51, 1951 October 4; Farber, Herman (Volume PIBMRI-259-51)
    R-259-51
    PIB 200
  - The Steady State and Transient Analysis of the Doubler and Full Wave Magnetic Amplifier with Free Excitation for "Rectangular" Hysteresis Core Material and Resistive Load, PIBMRI-260-51, 1951 October 25; Erkmen, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-260-51)
    R-260-51
    PIB 201
    Project Design NR-075-214
  - Microwave Network Theory and Applications, PIBMRI-262-51, 1951 September; Marcuvitz, Nathan; Oliner, Arthur A. (Volume PIBMRI-262-51)
    R-262-51
    PIB 202
    Contract No. Nonr-292(00)
    Project Designation No. 075-215
  - A Class of Broad-Band Dissipative Matching Networks Designed on an Insertion - Loss Basis, PIBMRI-264-52, 1952 January 25; Carlin, Herbert J.; La Rosa, Richard (Volume PIBMRI-264-52)
    R-264-51
    PIB 203
  - The Influence of Rectifier Performance Upon the Steady State Performance of Self-Saturating Magnetic Amplifiers, PIBMRI-265-52, 1952 February 13; Boros, Victor B. (Volume PIBMRI-265-52)
    R-265-52
    PIB 204
  - Abstract Operator Methods in the Solution of Integral Equations and Boundary Value Problems, PIBMRI-266-52, 1952; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-266-52)
    R-266-52
    PIB 205
  - The Calibration of the Slotted Section for Precision Microwave Measurements, PIBMRI-267-52, 1952 March; Oliner, Arthur A. (Volume PIBMRI-267-52)
    R-267-52
    PIB 206
  - Design Specification for Calibrated Microwave Radiometer (X-Band), PIBMRI-268-52, 1952 April 25; Vasques, H. A. (Volume PIBMRI-268-52)
    R-268-52
    PIB 207
    ATI 162321
  - Guided Wave Concept in Electromagnetic Theory, PIBMRI-269-52, 1952 May 14; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-269-52)
    R-269-52
    PIB 208
    Contract Nonr-292(00), Project No. 075-215
  - Second Quarterly Report June 15, 1952 to Sept. 15, 1952 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations, PIBMRI-270.7-52, 1952 November 11; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-270.7-52)
    R-270.7-52
    PIB 209.7
    AD 222
    Contract No. DA-36-039-sc-15511
  - Third Quarterly Report R-270.8-53, PIB-209.8 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations September 15, 1952 to December 14, 1952 Prepared for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-270.8-52, 1953 January 23; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-270.8-52)
    R-270.8-53
    PIB 209.8
    AD 1279
  - Fourth Quarterly Report R-270.11-53, PIB-209.11 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations December 15, 1952 to March 14, 1953 Prepared for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-270.11-53, 1953 May 21; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-270.11-53)
    R-270.11-53
    PIB 209.11
    AD 13099
  - Fifth Quarterly Report R-270.14-53, PIB-209.14 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations March 15, 1953 to June 14, 1953 Prepared for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-270.14-53, 1953 July 29; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-270.14-53)
    R-270.14-53
    PIB 209-14
    AD 17690
  - Sixth Quarterly Report R-270.17-53, PIB-209.17 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations June 15, 1953 to September 15, 1953 Prepared for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-270.17-53, 1953 November 19; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Box PIBMRI-270.17-53)
    R-270.17 53
    PIB 209.17
    AD 25570
  - Seventh Quarterly Report R-270.20-53, PIB-209.20 on Dielectric Breakdown Investigations September 15, 1953 to December 15, 1953 Prepared for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-270.20-53, 1954 February 10; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute. (Volume PIBMRI-270.20-53)
    R-270.20-54
    PIB 209.20
    AD 28217
  - D-C Transient Response of Single Energy Non-Linear Circuits, PIBMRI-271-52, 1952 July 28; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-271-52)
    R-271-52
    PIB 210
    Contract No. N6ori-98
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period May 1, 1952 to July 31, 1952 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.5-52, 1952 October 7; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.5-52)
    R-272.5-52
    PIB 211.5
    AD 4053
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period August 1, 1952 to October 31, 1952 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.6-52, 1952 December 15; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.6-52)
    R-272.6-52
    PIB 211.6
    AD 2346
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period November 1, 1952 to January 31, 1953 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.9-53, 1953 March 17; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.9-53)
    R-272.9-53
    PIB 211.9
    AD 10035
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period February 1, 1953 to April 30, 1953 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.13-53, 1953 June 19; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.13-53)
    R-272.13-53
    PIB 211.13
    AD 18685
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period May 1, 1953 to July 31, 1953 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.15-53, 1953 October 6; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.15-53)
    R-272.15-53
    PIB 211.15
    AD 23 020
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period August 1, 1953 to October 31, 1953 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.18-53, 1953 November 24; Carlin, Herbert J.; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.18-53)
    R-272.18-53
    PIB 211.18
    AD 27972
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period November 1, 1953 to January 31, 1954 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.21-54, 1954 March 25; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.21-54)
    R-272.21-54
    PIB 211.21
    AD 32664
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering Period February 1, 1954 to April 30, 1954 on Mount Assemblies for Microwave Powermeters for Signal Corps Engineering Laboratories, PIBMRI-272.24-54, 1954 June 2; James, Allan V. (Volume PIBMRI-272.24-54)
    R-272.24-54
    PIB 211.24
    AD 41211
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of June 1, to August 31, 1952 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.2-52, 1952 November 13; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-273.2-52)
    R-273.2-52
    PIB 212.2
    AD 4735
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of September 1, to November 30, 1952 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.3-53, 1953 January 27; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.3-53)
    R-273.3-53
    PIB 212.3
    AD 10039
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of December 1, 1952 to February 28, 1953 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.4-53, 1953 May 13; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.4-53)
    R-273.4-53
    PIB 212.4
    AD 14435
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of March 1, 1953 to May 1, 1953 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.6-53, 1953 July 30; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.6-53)
    R-273.6-53
    PIB 212.6
    AD 21876
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of June 1, 1953 to August 31, 1953 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.9-53, 1953 October 26; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.9-53)
    Technial report number(s)
    R-273.9
    PIB 212.9
    AD 32556
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of September 1, 1953 to November 30, 1953 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.12-54, 1954 Februrary 17; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.12-54)
    R-273.12-54
    PIB 212.12
    AD 32666
  - Quarterly Progress Report Covering the Period of December 1, 1953 to February 28, 1954 on Contract No. AF-30(602)-18, PIBMRI-273.15-54, 1954 May 28; Carlin, Herbert J.; Sucher, Max (Volume PIBMRI-273.15-54)
    R-273.15-54
    PIB 212.15
    AD 41203
  - A Simple Microwave Power Bridge Employing a Calibrated Decade Box, PIBMRI-274-52, 1952 July 8; Sweet, Leonard (Volume PIBMRI-274-52)
    R-274-52
    PIB 213
    Contract AF-30(602)-18
  - The Evaluation of a Sectionalized Shielded Enclosure, PIBMRI-275-52, 1952 July 11; Castriota, L.; Schwartz, L.; Vasques, H. A. (Volume PIBMRI-275-52)
    R-275-52
    PIB 214
    Contract No. AF-28(099)-8
  - The Use of Magnetic Amplifiers to Drive Two-Phase Servo Motors, PIBMRI-276-52, 1952 July; Kabrisky, M. J. (Volume PIBMRI-276-52)
    R-276-52
    PIB 215
    Contract Nonr-292(00), Project No. NR-075-215
  - A Study of Ferroresonant Series Circuit Using Sensitive Core Materials, PIBMRI-277-52, 1952 September 2; Bauer, Edwin W. (Volume PIBMRI-277-52)
    R-277-52
    PIB 216
  - Memorandum on Sub-Task "Instrumentation for Servo Testing," PIBMRI-278.1-52, 1952 July 30; Garik, Serge; Panzer, Marvin (Volume PIBMRI-278.1-52)
    R-278.1-52
    PIB 217.1
    Contract AF30(120)-490
  - Second Quarterly Report October 1, 1952 to December 31, 1952 An Investment of the Broadband Limits of Microwave Components, PIBMRI-279.4-53, 1953 April 20; Wind, Moe (Volume PIBMRI-279.4-53)
    R-279.4-53
    PIB 218.4
    AD 16899
    Contract DA-36-039 sc-42489
  - Fourth Progress Report July 1, 1953 to September 30, 1953 An Investment of the Broadband Limits of Microwave Components, PIBMRI-279.13-53, 1953 January 19; Griemsmann, John W. E.; Kasai, George S. (Volume PIBMRI-279.13-53)
    R-279.13-53
    PIB 218.13
    Dept. of the Army Project No. 3-26-00-602
    Signal Corps Project No. 32-2006C
- Series VI: Report numbers PIBMRI 301-400
  - The Reactance of a Symmetrical Pair of Strips in Rectangular Waveguide, PIBMRI-1158-63, 1963 April 23; Lewin, L (Volume PIBMRI-1158-63)
    PIBMRI-1158-63
    Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories.